[narrator] In order to become kings,
the Chimera Ants
have spread across the world,
committing acts of utmost tyranny
wherever they go.
[imperceptible]
[gasps] Huh?
Huh?
[Flutter] Huh?
Ah, is that all? I see.
[gasps]
[both gasp]
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in English]
[singer singing in Japanese]
INFILTRATION X AND X SELECTION
[Gon] Informants?
[Killua] Yeah.
Expose an enemy spy, get a reward.
When they rack up enough informant points,
the entire group is promoted.
But you commit a crime,
or you provide them false intel,
then the entire group is given punishment.
Carrot and stick, huh?
so if a whole group tries to escape,
their remaining family can be executed
or imprisoned for life.
If a family is caught
trying to escape together,
they'll be executed on the spot.
making up false stories like,
"In other countries, half the people
starve to death before age ten."
Foreign aid
never gets to those who need it.
which they're using as a bargaining chip
in international politics,
Uh, no, I think I'm okay.
That was just a whole lot to take in.
and he probably heard it from Grandpa.
Oh. Yeah?
Yeah. A long time ago,
he had to infiltrate the place
in order to finish a job he was doing.
And I saw similar information
when I was looking around
the Hunter website.
The same system might still be in place.
-A town.
-Yeah, a tiny one.
They might also have certain practices
in place to root out suspected spies.
Wait here, okay?
[Killua] Nuh-uh.
Something's happened here.
-Someone's trying to hide it.
-Huh?
And they did a sloppy job, too.
[grunts]
But what's going on here?
I think this is
the true purpose of the rally.
When whole towns disappear,
nobody will even be suspicious.
They set it up perfectly.
The selection has begun.
All told,
that's about five million people.
Clearing out one town or city at a time
is more effective.
In that case, their concern
would just be coworkers or family,
anyone who would notice them missing.
But with everything going on
with the national rally,
and not getting in touch
wouldn't be suspicious at all.
The selection should go smoothly.
The capital city of Peijing
is in the southeast corner.
They'd need to start with western towns
and work east.
troublesome communication
between the villages
they can eliminate
any cause for commotion.
-But…
-[Killua] Hmm?
[Gon] That means they have to run
all around the country
to attack
all five million citizens, right?
If only 1% survives,
that gives them 50,000 soldiers.
Yeah, I know, but I mean before that.
then you'd probably need
a whole lot of help, wouldn't you?
Okay, so let's say that in ten days,
one Nen user can check 10,000 citizens.
That's, uh…
[groans]
-It's 500.
-Yeah, that.
[Killua] There can't be
that many Ants that can use Nen.
-Is that what you're saying?
-[Gon] Yeah.
I agree with you,
but it won't be that hard.
It isn't like they need Nen users
in order to check everyone out.
[gasps]
It's what that Chimera Ant used.
I'm guessing that it can automate victims
or, like Genthru's power,
control multiple people at once.
so the Manipulator
could force a victim's aura
to concentrate in his fist.
One punch alone
could easily create an army of 50,000,
[grunts]
[Killua] Well, it isn't all bad news.
If my theory's correct, this'll be easy.
We just cause a commotion,
and the selection will totally stop.
And then after that,
this'll all be a cinch.
You and I will just run around taking them
down one after another and wreaking havoc.
Right!
The problem is they'll detect us quickly.
[groans]
Once we make our move, they'll know.
If we want to go through
with the old man's plan,
then we should try to keep
as low a profile as we possibly can.
[Gon grunts]
If the selection really has already begun,
we can't just simply ignore it.
I'm with you. Let's go.
-Okay.
-But I'm gonna do it alone.
-Huh?
-You stay hidden.
Stay hidden?
But wouldn't it be better if we--
Don't forget our primary mission.
We have to take Pitou down.
That should be your focus.
You let me handle
everything else, all right?
[groans] Yeah, I get it.
-Do you?
-Huh?
Do you really think you get it?
Killua.
[clenching]
Then promise me something!
Don't make a move,
even if people are killed
right in front of you.
Promise me.
[gasps]
[grunts]
[sighs] I'll text you, okay?
Killua?
Sorry. Don't worry about it.
I'm just a little on edge.
[grunts softly]
[chuckles]
[man] What's this?
They're not citizens of this country.
That's for sure.
They look a little young to be spies,
but they're definitely strong.
Are they here to hunt down the King?
If so, I can't ignore them,
but I definitely don't want to fight
both of them at once,
or the silver-haired one on the left
at all.
I can tell he's strong
by the way he walks.
He might even rival a squadron leader.
[man gasps]
That kid is extraordinary.
[man chuckles]
Well, that's convenient.
[chorus playing on phonograph]
we will both find ourselves
in difficult positions.
[sighs]
Everything, all of it,
And don't forget
all our lives are on the line here too.
"Diego has committed"?
Like you're so innocent.
The wine you're drinking,
even the room you're standing in,
You mean, "We've committed,"
you son of a bitch.
Now then, Mr. Marcos,
[Knuckle] I don't like it.
Will you please calm yourself down?
and only 1% of them will survive!
Your point?
That means 495,000 people
have already been killed!
How can you be so damn calm?
Because if we lose our cool now,
it's a death sentence for billions more.
[Knuckle grunts angrily]
If this plan fails, then everybody dies,
and if we can't draw
the three Royal Guards away,
then even Chairman Netero
can't defeat the King.
So no matter what, we can't afford
to let them discover our existence
-[Knuckle growls]
-You must endure.
[Shoot] That's right.
[gasps]
If blaming me consoles you at all,
then go ahead.
But unless you've come up
with a better idea,
I would advise you
not to be too self-righteous.
[growls]
[fruit crunches]
[Gon] I hope Killua's okay.
He was acting kinda weird.
Maybe I should have stayed with him.
But if I'd followed him,
I bet he'd be pretty mad.
[gasps]
[growls]
-[grunts]
-[gasps]
You're not crushing me.
[Gon] It's a good thing
he seems to have the genes of a snake.
I really need to hide better.
But it's strange.
Why are there still soldier ants
in an area
they've already finished sorting?
Maybe there are extra lookouts here
because we're pretty near the border.
[grunts]
[wings flapping]
[upbeat music playing]
[Gon] Next time,
"Combination and Evolution."
Step right up!
This is a perfectly ordinary box,
but say the magic words--
[Killua] Wouldn't that be an illusion?
[singer singing in Japanese]